# DALE WHINHAM

Student of Computer Science, Newcastle University

http://dwhinham.github.io daleyo@gmail.com +44 (0) 781 841 7874 Newcastle-upon-Tyne, NE3 2TN, UK

## **PROFILE**

A highly-motivated, passionate and inquisitive programmer, electronics enthusiast and musician. Currently studying for an MSc in Computer Science (Games Engineering).

Formerly an IT Manager at a multi-national aerospace engineering company, I left after 4 years of service to pursue my dream of turning my coding hobby into a successful career in software engineering.

I'm looking to join an enthusiastic and vibrant team so that I can expand my knowledge by learning from the best, and for the opportunity to apply my skills and flexibility in order to contribute to exciting new projects.

## **RECENT PROJECTS**

**Screen-Space Ambient Occlusion** 

available on my portfolio

A C++/OpenGL (and ES) dissertation project completed for my BSc degree, implementing and measuring the performance of the SSAO deferred rendering technique for fast soft-shadows on both desktop and Android platforms.

ARM Mali SDK Code Samples

http://malideveloper.arm.com

A C++ and OpenGL ES native Android code sample, demonstrating how to use multisampled framebuffer objects and render-to-texture to achieve efficient antialiasing on the ARM Mali series of mobile GPUs.

MilkyTracker

http://milkytracker.org

I ported this open-source cross-platform music editor to Cocoa (macOS) using Objective-C and OpenGL in order to remove its dependencies on deprecated Mac APIs. This has given me substantial experience in mixing C, C++ and Objective-C together in one project.

I additionally contributed a new CMake-based build system, bugfixes for the app's Mac sound driver (Core Audio), a port of the app from SDL 1.x to SDL 2.x for Linux targets, and set up Travis/AppVeyor continuous integration.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Programming**

C • C++ • lava

Objective-C • Some assembly

Visual Studio • Xcode • Intellij

Android Studio • Eclipse

Git ■ CMake ■ Vim

SSH ■ Bash/Unix command-line

macOS • Android
Object-oriented programming

Cross-platform development
Cross-compilers • Emscripten

PHP • SQL • HTML5 • CSS

JavaScript • Perl • XAMPP

Libraries and Frameworks

SDL • OpenGL (and ES)

Bullet Physics • Cocoa

**Operating Systems** 

Windows ■ macOS
Linux ■ BSD family

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

HackNE 2014

Hosted at Hancock Museum, Newcastle

Participated in a Hackathon in a team with three other students. Awarded the main prizes from two sponsors (Bloomberg and Bede Gaming) for best use of APIs and for our creative use of hardware (Arduino/LED matrices).

### **EDUCATION**

2013-2017: BSc Computer Science (1st)

**Newcastle University** 

**Relevant modules:** Games Development (93%), Computer Graphics (86%), Programming for Games (86%), Gaming Simulations (83%), Games Project & Dissertation (83%).

2012-2013: Access to HE Diploma

**Newcastle College** 

Mathematics, Physics, IT - achieved Distinction in all three.

2003-2005: Secondary Education Dame Allan's Schools, Newcastle

9 GCSE subjects, grades A\*-B.

AS-levels in Music Technology (A), ICT (B), English (C).

## **EMPLOYMENT**

2015-2016 (placement year): Intern Software Engineer

ARM Ltd.

Developed code samples for the ARM Mali graphics SDK during a summer internship. Later worked on power management firmware for ARM-based system-on-chips.

2014 (June-August): App Developer

**Newcastle University** 

Designed and implemented an Android app and PHP/ MySQL backend to help students receiving support and counselling from the Student Wellbeing Service.

2008-2012: IT Manager

P3Voith Aerospace Ltd.

Responsible for all aspects of IT within the company, including procurement and deployment of hardware and software, and providing one-to-one technical support to employees across three UK offices.

### REFERENCES

I would be delighted to provide references on request.

#### Other Skills

- Ability to take responsibility for tasks and work independently
- Ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines
- Adaptable, flexible, and quick to pick up new development tools and techniques
- Good at problem-solving
- Great team-working and communications skills
- Excellent written English
- Excellent documentation and code-commenting skills, familiar with Doxygen
- Lots of experience with version control (Git), continuous integration, and code review systems (e.g. Gerrit)
- Great debugging skills; familiar with Visual Studio, Xcode and Intellij built-in debuggers
- Strong understanding of C/C++ pointers and dynamic memory allocation
- Understanding of multithreading and thread-safety
- A love of graphics and audiorelated programming
- A love of "close-to-the-metal" programming; enjoy producing code that directly accesses the hardware or operating system